HAOMIN CHEN

Google Scholar: https://www.linkedin.com/in/haomin-chen-jhu-cs/

Personal website: https://haomin-website.netlify.app/

263 Congressional Lane, Rockville, Maryland, 20852 (open to relocate)

 $(443) \cdot 630 \cdot 2698 \diamond$ haominchen 1234@gmail.com \diamond Google Scholar

SUMMARY

Applied Research Scientist working in Ericsson LynkAI for interpretable video translation. Graduated as a Computer Science Ph.D. from Johns Hopkins University with a background in interpretable computer vision systems for medical image analysis. Rich experience with computer vision, generative AI, and human-computer interaction. The first author of a Nature Partner Journal paper. Excellent communication skills and ability to work on multi-disciplinary teams.

EDUCATIONS

Johns Hopkins University

Jan 2018 - Dec 2022 (Degree Completed)

Doctor of Philosophy, Computer Science

Degree Awarded in May 2023

Advisors: Dr. Mathias Unberath, Dr. Gregory Hager

Baltimore, MD, USA

First author publications: 5 conference papers, 4 journal papers

First author of one Nature partner journal paper

Columbia University

Sep 2016 - Dec 2017

Master of Arts, Statistics Overall GPA: 4.1 / 4.0 New York City, NY, USA

Fudan University

Sep 2012 - Jun 2016

Bachelor of Science, Physics

Core GPA: 3.6 / 4.0

Shanghai, CHINA

SKILLS

Python, C++, Linux, Slurm, Docker, PyTorch, Tensorflow, Matlab, R, Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Computer Vision, Medical Image Analysis, Human-Computer Interaction, Interpretable Learning, Classification, Object Detection, Instance Segmentation, LLM, Generative AI, Audio Processing, Statistical Analysis

EXPERIENCES

Ericsson, Los Angeles

Feb 2023 - now

Applied Research Scientist

Los Angeles, CA, USA

Video Translation with Lip Sync and Preserving Tone by Generative AI

- · Created the largest dataset of talking head videos from YouTube with 13 languages & 600 hours.
- · Established multi-person & lingual audio/video synchronization, outperforming ElevenLabs.
- · Refined the facial landmark generation network for better articulation.
- · Used diffusion to achieve immersive lip synchronization in videos with translated audio.

Meta, Redmond

Jun 2022 - Oct 2022

Redmond, WA, USA

 $Research\ Intern$

2D-3D Style Transfer for VR

- · Achieved real-time inference and human interaction for personalized customization.
- · Preserved 3D visual reality and outperformed other methods in user experience.

- · Stylized 3D scene with 2D style images by differential rendering with PyTorch3D & nvdiffrast.
- · Learned quickly style transfer, 3D graphics, and rendering from scratch in one week.
- · Exceeded director/mentor/peers' expectations in internship review.

PingAn Technology, Bethesda

May 2019 - Dec 2019

Applied Research Intern

Bethesda, MD, USA

Fracture Detection in Pelvic Trauma X-rays

- · Deployed in Chang Gung Memorial Hospital in Taiwan and used by over 5000 patients.
- · First-author conference paper is accepted by ECCV 2020 with a poster presentation.
- · Improved detection AUC from 0.95 to 0.98 and fracture recall from 0.89 to 0.93 (FPR=0.1).
- · Mimicked radiologists to detect fractures by comparing bilateral symmetric regions.
- · Focused on anatomical asymmetry with contrastive learning.

NVIDIA, Bethesda

May 2018 - Dec 2018

Applied Research Intern

Bethesda, MD, USA

Multi-Abnormality Classification in Chest X-rays

- · First-author conference paper is accepted by MIDL 2019 with an oral presentation.
- · First-author journal paper is accepted by Medical Image Analysis (IF = 13.8).
- · Improved classification AUC from 0.87 to 0.89.
- · Robust to incompletely labeled data and preserved 85% performance drop.
- · Mimicked radiologists to classify abnormality with clinical taxonomy.
- · Established numerically stable method for calculation of CE loss of unconditional probabilities.

PingAn Technology, Shanghai

May 2017 - Aug 2017

Data Mining Scientist Intern

Shanghai, CHINA

Lung Nodule Detection in CT Scans

- · Achieved top 6 out of 2887 teams in the Skylake competition by Intel and Alibaba.
- · Applied 3D UNet with Pytorch & Faster RCNN with Caffe for detection in 1000 CT scans.
- · Utilized fusion methods to achieve false positive reduction.

Johns Hopkins University

Jan 2018 - Feb 2023

Research Assistant

Baltimore, MD, USA

Systematic Review for Interpretable ML in Medical Image Analysis

- · First-author journal paper is accepted in npj Digital Medicine (IF = 11.6).
- · Proposed interpretability as a relationship between end users instead of as a property of models.
- · Introduced guidelines to recommend first understanding end users before model design.
- · Conducted a systematic review in PubMed, EMBASE, and Compendex databases.
- · Identified 2508 records and included 68 articles.

Interpretable Cancer Subtyping with Cytopathology Images

- · First-author conference paper is accepted in ICML workshop.
- · Improved cancer subtyping AUC from 0.75 to 0.87 and provided interpretation.
- · Analyzed cell composition by cell segmentation deep features and rule-based learning.
- · Proved to be interpretable in a web-based user study with pathologists.

Interpretable High-Quality ROI Extraction with Cytopathology Images

- · First-author conference paper is accepted in MICCAI workshop.
- · Created automatic and interactive high-quality ROI extraction with deep clustering.
- \cdot Improved recall from 11% to 51% and speeded up by 10 times.

Pelvic Fracture Severity Grading with CT Scans

- · First-author journal paper under third-round review in IEEE TMI (IF = 10.6).
- · Applied Bayesian model to predict severity grading with AO/OTA clinical grading criterion.
- · Proposed Bayesian refinement to retrieve false-negative fractures.
- · Established augmented inference to calculate robust fracture confidence scores.

Automatic Splenic Injury Grading System with CT Scans

- · First-author journal paper is accepted in Emergency Radiology (IF = 1.59).
- · Proposed neuralsymbolic learning by following AAST clinical guidelines.
- · Created rule-based symbolic reasoning for severity grading with deep network findings.

SELECTED PUBLICATIONS

Journal papers:

- Haomin Chen*, Catalina Gomez*, Chien-Ming Huang, Mathias Unberath. Explainable Medical Imaging AI Needs Human-Centered Design: Guidelines and Evidence from a Systematic Review. (2022) npj Digital Medicine (IF=11.65) 5, 156.
- 2. *Haomin Chen*, Shun Miao, Daguang Xu, Gregory Hager, Adam Harrison. Deep hierarchical multi-label classification applied to chest X-ray abnormality taxonomies. (2020) **Medical Image Analysis (IF=13.82) 66**, 101811.
- 3. T. Y. Alvin Liu*, *Haomin Chen**, Catalina Gomez, Zelia Correa, Mathias Unberath. Direct Gene Expression Profile Prediction for Uveal Melanoma from Digital Cytopathology Images via Deep Learning. (2022) **Ophthalmology Science (IF=7.18)** 100240.
- 4. *Haomin Chen*, David Dreizin, Mathias Unberath. Toward automated interpretable AAST grading for blunt splenic injury. (2022) **Emergency Radiology (IF=1.59)**
- 5. David Dreizin, Bryan Nixon, Jiazhen Hu, Benjamin Albert, Chang Yan, Gary Yang, *Haomin Chen*, Yuanyuan Liang, Nahye Kim, Jean Jeudy, Guang Li, Elana B. Smith, Mathias Unberath. A pilot study of deep learning-based CT volumetry for traumatic hemothorax. (2022) Emergency Radiology (IF=1.59) DOI:10.1007/s10140-022-02087-5.

Conference papers:

- 1. **Haomin Chen***, Yirui Wang*, Kang Zheng, Weijian Li, Chi-Tung Chang, Adam P. Harrison, Jing Xiao, Gregory D. Hager, Le Lu, Chien-Hung Liao, Shun Miao. Anatomy-aware siamese network: Exploiting semantic asymmetry for accurate pelvic fracture detection in x-ray images. **ECCV** 2020.
- 2. *Haomin Chen*, Shun Miao, Daguang Xu, Gregory D. Hager, Adam P. Harrison. Deep hierarchical multi-label classification of chest X-ray images. **MIDL** 2019.
- 3. **Haomin Chen**, T. Y. Alvin Liu, Catalina, Gomez, Mathias Unberath. An Interpretable Algorithm for Uveal Melanoma Subtyping from Whole Slide Cytology Images. **IMLH**, 2021. (*ICML workshop*).
- 4. *Haomin Chen*, T. Y. Alvin Liu, Zelia M. Correa, Mathias Unberath. An Interactive Approach to Region of Interest Selection in Cytologic Analysis of Uveal Melanoma Based on Unsupervised Clustering. **OMIA**, 2020 (MICCAI workshop).
- 5. David Dreizin, *Haomin Chen*, Alexander Upegui, Guang Li, Mathias Unberath. Blunt splenic trauma: accuracy of automated active bleed and contained vascular injury detection on CT with Faster R-CNN. **ASER** 2022 and **RSNA** 2022.

- David Dreizin, *Haomin Chen*, Alexander Upegui, Guang Li, Mathias Unberath. Blunt splenic trauma: automated splenic parenchymal disruption volumes for decision making in patients with no vascular injuries on CT. ASER 2022 and RSNA 2022.
- 7. Yifan Gao*, *Haomin Chen**, Catalina Gomez*, Sophie Cai, Craig K. Jones, Adrienne Scott, Mathias Unberath. An Interpretable Approach to Identifying Sea Fan Neovascularization in Ultra-Widefield Color Fundus Photographs of Patients With Sickle Cell Hemoglobinopathy. **SPIE**, 2021.
- 8. T. Y. Alvin Liu, Hongxi Zhu, *Haomin Chen*, J. Fernando Arevalo, Ferdinand K. Hui, Paul H. Yi, Jinchi Wei, Mathias Unberath, Zelia M. Correa. Gene Expression Profile Prediction in Uveal Melanoma Using Deep Learning: A Pilot Study for the Development of an Alternative Survival Prediction Tool. **Ophthalmology Retina**, 2020.

AWARDS

| Mentor award in the Howard County Public School. | April 2022 |
|---|------------|
| National College Students Mathematics Competition, National Silver Medal. | Oct 2013 |
| National College Students Mathematics Model Contest, the third prize of Shanghai. | Oct 2014 |
| Second-class scholarship of Fudan University. | May~2015 |
| Mensa Member in China. | May 2016 |